# Parshan Pakiman

★ parshanpakiman.github.io/homepage

in linkedin.com/in/parshan-pakiman

ngithub.com/parshanpakiman

ppakim2@uic.edu

**(\*)** +1 312 493 1304

**2** February 2021

#### **OVERVIEW**

I am a Ph.D. candidate in Information and Decision Sciences at the University of Illinois at Chicago. My research advances solution techniques to high-dimensional decision-making problems. I develop Reinforcement Learning (RL) algorithms that self-adapt to data by learning a model of the data generation process and using this model to deliver better decisions. My research contributes to the literature on RL, inverse RL, machine learning, online learning, and high-dimensional sampling. I employ state-of-the-art platforms such as Gurobi, PyTorch, and Nevergrad to test my RL algorithms on real-world applications.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC), Chicago, IL

Ph.D. in: Information and Decision Sciences
Thesis title: Self-adapting Reinforcement Learning

Co-advisors: Professors Selva Nadarajah and Negar Soheili

University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC), Chicago, IL

M.Sc. in: Business Analytics

University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran

B.Sc. in: Applied Mathematics

WORK EXPERIENCES

 Working with a major tech provider in fast-fashion sector to adaptively learn changing customer demand and modify pricing strategies to maximize revenue (Link to the resulting research paper).

 Collaborated with Foresight ROI to design a framework for mining past marketing data and for optimizing future marketing campaigns (Link to the resulting paper).

 Teaching and implementation experience in graduate classes with data mining, statistical learning, machine learning, and operations management.

 Collaborator on a multi-university and industry initiative to develop an open-source reinforcement learning and approximate dynamic programming platform to solve business problems.

 $-\,$  Reviewing research articles for multiple journals in the areas of Operations Research and E-commerce.

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Studying reinforcement learning problems that the available data for learning is generated from a decision making process and is useful to uncover the dynamics of the data generation process.
- Solving large-scale sequential decision making problems by combining reinforcement learning, approximate dynamic programming, randomized and high-dimensional sampling, and optimization techniques.
- Developing data-driven algorithms with online and offline data availability that leverage forecasts to compute robust decisions in application domains such as pricing, retailing, e-commerce, and marketing.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## Journal Papers

Self-adapting Robustness in Demand Learning. Coauthors: Boxiao Chen, Selvaprabu Nadarajah, Stefanus Jasin. Fa
 Submitted to Operations Research. Link.

Self-guided Approximate Linear Programs. Coauthors: Selvaprabu Nadarajah, Negar Soheili, Qihang Lin. First round major revision at Management Science. Link.

#### **Conference Papers**

 Guiding Agents via Menus when Optimization and/or Learning Costs are High. Coauthors: Selvaprabu Nadarajah, Yun Fong Lim. Submitted to ICML 2021.

SMOILE: A Shopper Marketing Optimization and Inverse Learning Engine. Coauthors: Abhilash Reddy Chenreddy, Selvaprabu Nadarajah, Ranganathan Chandrasekaran, Rick Abens. Proceedings of the 25th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining. Acceptance rate is 6.4%. Link.

## **Workshop Papers**

Self-guided Approximate Linear Programs. Coauthors: Selvaprabu Nadarajah, Negar Soheili, Qihang Lin. Accepted in NeurIPS workshop on Self-Supervised Learning – Theory and Practice, NeurIPS 2020. Link.

Summer 2019

Since Spring 2019

Spring 2017 -(Expected) Fall 2021

Spring 2017 -(Expected) Fall 2021

Fall 2012 - Fall 2016

Fall 2017 - Summer 2019

Since Fall 2014

Fall 2019

Since Fall 2019

ll 2020

Spring 2021

- Menu Optimization for Sustainable Warehousing. Coauthors: Selvaprabu Nadarajah, Yun Fong Lim.

Convex Optimization using Random Features. Coauthors: Selva Nadarajah, Negar Soheili.

Present

Present

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming language: Python, C++, C, R, Java, HTML, JavaScript

Python package: NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SciKitLearn, PyTorch, GurobiPy, Nevergrad, Pyomo

Software: Matlab, Tableau, Microsoft/Libre Office, RapidMiner

Operating systems: Linux, Windows, MacOS

#### **AWARDS AND HONORS**

Doctoral fellowship: Department of Information and Decision Sciences, University of Illinois at Chicago Top student award: Department of Mathematics, Statistics and Computer Science, University of Tehran

Technical qualification: RoboCup Iran open, soccer 2D simulation league

Technical qualification: Khwarizmi international award, soccer 2D simulation league

Since Spring 2017

Fall 2016 Fall 2016 Fall 2010

### **INVITED TALKS**

## Self-adapting Robustness in Demand Learning

INFORMS Annual Meeting, Virtual

- INFORMS Revenue Management and Pricing Student Live Paper Series, Link, Virtual

Fall 2020 Fall 2020

## Self-guided Approximate Linear Programs

- POMS 30th Annual Conference, Washington D.C.

INFORMS Annual Meeting, Phoenix, AZ

- POMS 29th Annual Conference, Houston, TX

Spring 2019

Fall 2018 Spring 2018

## SMOILE: A Shopper Marketing Optimization and Inverse Learning Engine

ACM SIGKDD, International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining, Link, Anchorage, AK

Summer 2019

#### POSTER PRESENTATIONS

#### Self-guided Approximate Linear Programs

- NeurIPS 2020, Workshop on Self-Supervised Learning - Theory and Practice, Link, Virtual

Fall 2020

## SMOILE: A Shopper Marketing Optimization and Inverse Learning Engine

ACM SIGKDD, International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining, Link, Anchorage, AK

Summer 2019

## **SERVICE**

## Reviewer

Annals of Operations Research

Computers & Operations Research

Electronic Commerce Research

Information Systems and Operational Research

## Since Fall 2020

Since Spring 2019

Since Spring 2018

Since Fall 2018

## **TEACHING EXPERIENCES**

## Lecturer for statistical models and methods for business analytics

Applications of regression, classification and likelihood maximization, Link.

Spring 2019 - Fall 2019

Since Spring 2017

# Teaching Assistant, University of Illinois at Chicago

- Advanced text analytics for Business (IDS 566)
- Business data mining (IDS 472)
- Business forecasting (IDS 476)
- Data science for online customer analytics (IDS 594)
- Introduction to operations management (IDS 532)
- Statistical models and methods for business analytics (IDS 575)

#### Teaching Assistant, University of Tehran

- Advanced text analytics for Business (IDS 566)
- Introduction to numerical analysis and scientific computing
- Numerical linear algebra

Spring 2014 - 2016